<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting Started on Githuka Noteonomy Project [gnp]</title>
    <link>https://gnp.githuka.com/getting-started/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting Started on Githuka Noteonomy Project [gnp]</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 15:26:15 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gnp.githuka.com/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About the gnp project</title>
      <link>https://gnp.githuka.com/getting-started/about_gnp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 19:01:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnp.githuka.com/getting-started/about_gnp/</guid>
      <description>[gnp] The Githuka Noteonomy Project is a longterm learning process about the interesting word of connected and autonomous vehicle systems. In this project we shall using a real vehicle - Nissan Note E11 2008, adding devices in it towards converting it into a connected car and attain some level of autonomy in the future. The Nissan Note E11 2008 Model is a 5 door mini MPV hatchback manufactured by Nissan Japan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connected Vehicles</title>
      <link>https://gnp.githuka.com/getting-started/connected_vehicle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jan 2022 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnp.githuka.com/getting-started/connected_vehicle/</guid>
      <description>Connected vehicles are cars which can be able to bi-directionally share data with their surroundings. The cars can be able to talk with various systems around them.
Connetivity Modes  V2I &amp;ldquo;Vehicle to Infrastructure&amp;rdquo;: The technology captures data generated by the vehicle and provides information about the infrastructure to the driver. The V2I technology communicates information about safety, mobility or environment-related conditions. V2V &amp;ldquo;Vehicle to Vehicle&amp;rdquo;: The technology communicates information about speed and position of surrounding vehicles through a wireless exchange of information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous Vehicles</title>
      <link>https://gnp.githuka.com/getting-started/autonomous/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnp.githuka.com/getting-started/autonomous/</guid>
      <description>A self-driving car, also known as an autonomous vehicle (AV), driverless car, or robotic car (robo-car),is a car incorporating vehicular automation, that is, a ground vehicle that is capable of sensing its environment and moving safely with little or no human input.The future of this technology may have an impact on multiple industries and other circumstances.
Self-driving cars combine a variety of sensors to perceive their surroundings, such as thermographic cameras, radar, lidar, sonar, GPS, odometry and inertial measurement units.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Presentations</title>
      <link>https://gnp.githuka.com/getting-started/ppts/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 15:26:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gnp.githuka.com/getting-started/ppts/</guid>
      <description>PyCon 2017 Youtube Video
The first ever PyCon Conference in Kenya was held USIU-Africa from September 28-29 2017. The conference brought together software developers techies, business pepple startups, learning institutions and others that have either an interest or a stake in the open source python programming language, and related technologies in its ecosystem.
The presentation can be downloaded here.
AIKenya Show And Tell 2019 AI Kenya is a fast growing community aimed at bringing together like-minded people to discuss, build and grow the Artificial Intelligence and Data Science ecosystem in Kenya and East Africa.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
